Guide to the Lyman Hoover Papers
Yale University Divinity School Library
- Correspondence, 1902-1970; Series I
  - General Correspondence
    - Sme - Smith, Dr. Frank R. (Box 14, Folder 314)
    - Smith, Helen - Sp (Box 14, Folder 315)
    - St - Stim (Box 14, Folder 316)
    - Stir - Stu (Box 14, Folder 317)
    - Su - Sw - (Box 14, Folder 318)
    - Scarsdale Community Baptist Church, 1950-1955 (Box 14, Folder 319)
    - Schmoker, J. Benjamin (see: Committee on Friendly Relations among Foreign Students)
    - Schwarz, Kurt and Martha; Salser, Richard, 1941-1964 (Box 15, Folder 320)
    - Shanghai American School (see also: Carolyn Morris), 1937-1948 Mar (Box 15, Folder 321)
    - Shanghai American School, 1948 Apr-1949 (Box 15, Folder 322)
    - Shanghai Tiffin Club, 1934-1967 (Box 15, Folder 323)
    - Sharp, Thomas S. (see also: Student Volunteer Movement for Missions), 1922-1938 (Box 15, Folder 324)
    - Shaw, Robert M., 1943-1950 (Box 15, Folder 325)
    - Shedd, Clarence; Sino-Foreign Group of Shanghai (see: YMCA correspondence), 1923-1966 (Box 15, Folder 326)
    - Snipes, P. D., 1926-1932 (Box 15, Folder 327)
    - Society of Friends of Moslems in China (see also: Hu, C.S. Richard; Pickens, Claude), 1945 (Box 15, Folder 328)
    - Stauffer, Milton, 1923-1928, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 329)
    - Steinberg, David, 1957-1965 (Box 15, Folder 330)
    - Strickler, Wyatt, 1921-1966 n.d. (Box 15, Folder 331)
    - Student Volunteer Movement (see also Sharp,Thomas; Stauffer, Milton; Wilder, Robert), 1921-1934 (Box 15, Folder 332)
    - Student Volunteer Movement, 1939-1951 (Box 15, Folder 333)
    - Sweet, Lennig and Helen (see also: YMCA correspondence, United China Relief), 1933-1966 (Box 15, Folder 334)
    - Ta - Ti (Box 15, Folder 335)
    - To - Ty (Box 15, Folder 336)
    - Thant, U, 1957-1962 (Box 15, Folder 337)
    - Thomas, Winburn (see also: YMCA correspondence), 1947-1948 (Box 15, Folder 338)
    - Timperley, H. J., 1935-1948, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 339)
    - Tu, Y. C. (see also: YMCA correspondence), 1946-1947 (Box 15, Folder 340)
    - Tucker, Luther and Jo (see also: YMCA correspondence), 1938-1966 (Box 15, Folder 341)
    - Twinem, Mrs. Paul D., 1942-1944, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 342)
    - U (Box 15, Folder 343)
    - United Board for Christian Colleges in China, 1950-1953 (Box 15, Folder 344)
    - United Board for Christian Higher Education in China, 1959-1967, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 345)
    - United China Relief, 1941-1946 (Box 16, Folder 346)
    - United Christian Missionary Society, 1922-1931 (Box 16, Folder 347)
    - United Christian Missionary Society, 1937-1938, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 348)
    - United Nations Relief and Rehabilitation Administration, 1945 (Box 16, Folder 349)
    - United Service to China, 1947-1948 (Box 16, Folder 350)
    - United States Government Agencies, 1930-1954 (Box 16, Folder 351)
    - V (Box 16, Folder 352)
    - Van Dusen, Henry P. (see also: YMCA correspondence), 1960 (Box 16, Folder 353)
    - Vassar College, 1943-1953 (Box 16, Folder 354)
    - Wa (Box 16, Folder 355)
    - We - Wh (Box 16, Folder 356)
    - Wi (Box 16, Folder 357)
    - Wo - Wy (Box 16, Folder 358)
    - Weigle, Luther A., 1943-1948 (Box 16, Folder 359)
    - Wilbur, Hollis (see also: YMCA correspondence and Shanghai American School), 1932-1962 (Box 16, Folder 360)
    - Wilder, Robert Parmelee, 1921-1928 (Box 16, Folder 361)
    - Williams, Margaret, 1924 (Box 16, Folder 362)
    - World's Student Christian Federation, 1945-1948 (Box 16, Folder 363)
    - Y (Box 16, Folder 364)
    - Yale Campbell Club, 1948-1953 (Box 16, Folder 365)
    - Yale Divinity School, 1921-1927 (Box 16, Folder 366)
    - Yale University, 1939-1977 (Box 16, Folder 367)
    - Yang, Arthur, 1943-1944 (Box 16, Folder 368)
    - Yang, May, 1944-1966 (Box 16, Folder 369)
    - YMCA, 1923-1930 Nov (Box 16, Folder 370-380)
    - YMCA, 1930 Dec-1939 Sep (Box 17, Folder 381-412)
    - YMCA, 1939 Oct-1944 Jul (Box 18, Folder 413-428)
    - YMCA, 1944 Aug-1946 Aug (Box 19, Folder 429-442)
    - YMCA, 1946 Sep-1947 (Box 20, Folder 443-457)
    - YMCA, 1948 Jan-1949 Apr (Box 21, Folder 458-469)
    - YMCA, 1949 May-1957 (Box 22, Folder 470-482)
    - YMCA, 1958-1967, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 483-486)
    - YMCA (correspondence w/ HKH), 1928,1938, 1940-1941 (Box 23, Folder 487)
    - YMCA (correspondence w/ HKH), 1942 (Box 23, Folder 488)
    - YMCA (correspondence w/ HKH), 1943 (Box 23, Folder 489)
    - YMCA (correspondence w/ HKH), 1944 Jan-Jun (Box 23, Folder 490)
    - YMCA (correspondence w/ HKH), 1944 Jul-1945, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 491)
    - Young Women's Christian Association, 1939-1947, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 492)
    - Z (Box 23, Folder 493)
    - Zimmerman, Walter (see also: YMCA correspondence), 1956-1965 (Box 23, Folder 494)
    - Zwemer, Samuel W., 1922-1951 (Box 23, Folder 495)
    - Unidentified Correspondence (arranged by first name) A - L (Box 23, Folder 496)
    - Unidentified Correspondence (arranged by first name) M - W. illegible (Box 23, Folder 497)
- Notes/Subject File, 1900-1975; Series II
  The material in this series is arranged alphabetically by topic.
  - Addresses and mailing lists, 1930-1935 (Box 24, Folder 498)
  - Addresses and mailing lists, 1965, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 499)
  - American Association of Shanghai, 1938-1948, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 500)
  - American Friends of Vietnam, 1956 (Box 24, Folder 501)
  - American Information Committee, 1938-1940 (Box 24, Folder 502)
  - American Information Committee, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 503)
  - Asia Foundation, 1954-1976, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 504-508)
  - Bible and prayer studies (Box 25, Folder 509)
  - Books loaned out, 1945, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 510)
  - Burma, 1949-1957 (Box 25, Folder 511)
  - China after the Communist takeover, 1948 (Box 25, Folder 512)
  - China after the Communist takeover, 1950-1958 (Box 25, Folder 513)
  - China after the Communist takeover, 1965 (Box 25, Folder 514)
  - China - history (Box 25, Folder 515-517)
  - China, miscellaneous material, 1932-1940, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 518)
  - Chinese art and photographs, 1964-1966 (Box 25, Folder 519, Box OV1)
  - Chinese Protestant leaders - list compiled by M. Searle Bates, 1971 (Box 26, Folder 520)
  - Chinese Student Movement - ideological background (paper by Kiang Wen Han) (Box 26, Folder 521)
  - Chinese Students' Christian Association, 1924, 1948 (Box 26, Folder 522)
  - Chinese Students' Christian Association, 1949-1950 (Box 26, Folder 523)
  - Chinese Students' Christian Association, 1951, n.d (Box 26, Folder 524)
  - Church Center for the United Nations:Symposium on Southeast Asia and China, 1965 (Box 26, Folder 525)
  - Committee for a Free Asia, Inc., 1951-1953, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 526-528)
  - Course notes: Chinese Culture and Institutions, 1926 (Box 27, Folder 530)
  - Course notes: Christian Ethics (R. Niebuhr), 1937 (Box 27, Folder 531)
  - Course notes: Cultural Processes (Lipton), 1947 (Box 27, Folder 532)
  - Course notes: General Education Seminar (Hill), 1947-1948 (Box 27, Folder 533)
  - Course notes: Government and Politics in the Far East - China (Rowe), 1947 (Box 27, Folder 534)
  - Course notes: Government and Politics in the Far East - Japan and Soviet Asia (Rowe), 1947 (Box 27, Folder 535)
  - Course notes: Government and Politics in Eastern Asia (Rowe), 1948 (Box 27, Folder 536)
  - Course notes: History of Islam (Archer, Torrey), 1923, 1926 (Box 28, Folder 537)
  - Course notes: History of the Christian Church in China (Latourette), 1926 (Box 28, Folder 538)
  - Course notes: Miscellaneous, 1923-1926, n.d (Box 28, Folder 539)
  - Course notes: New Testament Theology (Porter), 1926-1927 (Box 28, Folder 540)
  - Course notes: Philosophy of Science and Culture (Northrup), 1947-1948 (Box 28, Folder 541)
  - Course notes: Philosophy of Science and Culture (Northrup), 1948 (Box 28, Folder 542)
  - Course notes: Religion in Higher Education, 1937 (Box 28, Folder 543)
  - Course notes: Religions of China (Latourette), 1926-1927 (Box 29, Folder 544)
  - Course notes: Religious Education in China (Lew), 1927 (Box 29, Folder 545)
  - Course notes: Social Structure (Lipton), 1948 (Box 29, Folder 546)
  - Course notes: Systematic Theology (Macintosh), 1925 (Box 29, Folder 546A)
  - Course notes: YMCA Seminar (Cheney), 1937 (Box 29, Folder 547)
  - Debate speeches/notes by LH, 1916, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 548)
  - Fellowship of Reconciliation, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 549)
  - Foreign Policy Association, 1956 (Box 29, Folder 550)
  - Games and songs for groups (Chinese language material) (Box 29, Folder 551)
  - India, 1958-1963 (Box 29, Folder 552)
  - Indonesia, 1950-1963, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 553)
  - Japan, 1936-1952 (Box 30, Folder 554)
  - Japan, 1954-1960, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 555)
  - Maps (Box 30, Folder 556, Box OV1)
  - Maps (Box 30, Folder 557-558)
  - Material related to learning Arabic, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 559)
  - Material related to learning Chinese, c. 1931-1932 (Box 30, Folder 560-567)
  - Miscellaneous advertisements and printed material from China (Box 31, Folder 568)
  - Miscellaneous calling cards and greeting cards (Box 31, Folder 569-570)
  - Miscellaneous Chinese language material (duplicated) (Box 32, Folder 571-573)
  - Miscellaneous Chinese language material (holograph) (Box 32, Folder 574)
  - Miscellaneous invitations (Box 32, Folder 575)
  - Miscellaneous notes, c. 1923-1930 (Box 32, Folder 576-578)
  - Miscellaneous notes, c. 1929-1975 (Box 33, Folder 579-589)
  - Miscellaneous organizations in China (Box 33, Folder 590)
  - Missionary preparation: study by LH (Correspondence with various institutions), 1948 (Box 33, Folder 591-595)
  - Muslims in China: Note: Correspondence with the following people also relates to Muslims in China: Andrew, G. Findlay; Harris, George K.;Hayward, Harold; Hu, C.S. Richard; Jeffrey, Arthur; Mu, Wen Fu; Pickens, Claude; Price, Frank W.; Sargent, Clyde; Young, D.S. Sadi, 1920-1942 (Box 34, Folder 596-607)
  - Muslims in China, 1943-1958 (Box 35, Folder 608-609)
  - Muslims in China (biographical information), n.d. (Box 35, Folder 610)
  - Muslims in China (calling cards and envelopes) (Box 35, Folder 611)
  - Muslims in China (Chinese and Arabic language material) (Box 35, Folder 612)
  - Muslims in China (Chinese and Arabic language material, including Chinese Koran) (Box 35, Folder 613)
  - Muslims in China (Chinese and Arabic language material) (Box 36, Folder 614)
  - Muslims in China (holograph notes), n.d. (Box 36, Folder 615)
  - Muslims in China (holograph notes), n.d. (Box 36, Folder 616)
  - Muslims in China (typescript and printed material) (Box 36, Folder 617)
  - Northford Congregational Church - pastorate of LH, 1924-1928 (Box 36, Folder 618)
  - Peiping Union Church (Box 36, Folder 619)
  - Peking city guides, 1931-1936,n.d. (Box 36, Folder 620-621)
  - Political situation in China, 1938-1941, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 622-624)
  - Sermon notes and orders of worship, c. 1923-1945, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 625-630)
  - Sermon notes (of Guy I. Hoover?), 1900-1913 (Box 37, Folder 631)
  - Servants, 1937, 1939, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 632)
  - Shanghai American School, 1937-1949 (Box 37, Folder 633-634)
  - Shanghai American School, 1937-1949 (Box 38, Folder 635-636)
  - Shanghai Tiffin Club, 1949-1965 (Box 38, Folder 637-640)
  - Student Christian Movement, 1949, n.d. (Box 38, Folder 641)
  - Student situation in China, 1939, n.d. (Box 38, Folder 642)
  - Student Volunteer Movement, 1922-1923 (Box 38, Folder 643)
  - United Board for Christian Higher Education in China, 1957-1965 (Box 38, Folder 644)
  - United Service to China, 1947, 1949 (Box 38, Folder 645)
  - Women in China (article by E. B. Copland) (Box 38, Folder 646)
  - Worship manual (Chinese language), n.d. (Box 38, Folder 647)
  - YMCA in China: Financial material, 1939-1948, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 648)
  - YMCA in China: Financial material miscellaneous receipts (Box 39, Folder 649)
  - YMCA in China: Meeting minutes, 1928-1949 (Box 39, Folder 650-663)
  - YMCA in China: Miscellaneous holograph notes (Box 40, Folder 664)
  - YMCA in China: Miscellaneous printed publications (Chinese language), 1934-1949,n.d. (Box 40, Folder 665-668)
  - YMCA in China: Miscellaneous typescript material, 1930-1948, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 669)
  - YMCA in China: Periodical publications, 1930-1946 (Box 40, Folder 670)
  - YMCA in China: Periodical publications Chinese language (Box 40, Folder 671)
  - YMCA in China: Personnel, 1931-1958 (Box 40, Folder 672)
  - YMCA in China: Personnel, 1975, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 673)
  - YMCA in China: Relief and reconstruction, 1934-1949,n.d. (Box 41, Folder 674-686)
  - YMCA in China: Reports, statements, 1927-1955,n.d. (Box 42, Folder 687-694)
  - YMCA in China: Student division, 1930-1950, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 695)
  - YMCA in China: Student Secretaries' Reading Party Materials, 1940, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 696)
  - YMCA in China: Study group materials, 1937-1965 (Box 42, Folder 697)
  - YMCA in China: Study group materials on Sino-Japanese conflict, 1939-1940 (Box 43, Folder 698-699)
  - YMCA in China: Training programs, 1932-1934 (Box 43, Folder 700)
  - YMCA in China: Training programs, 1946-1948, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 701)
  - YMCA in China: Vocational education programs, 1948-1949, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 702)
  - YMCA - US and International: Asian Leaders Conferences, 1954, 1967 (Box 44, Folder 703)
  - YMCA - US and International: Budget and fund-raising material, 1930-1965, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 704)
  - YMCA - US and International: Committees and commissions served by LH, 1946-1965 (Box 44, Folder 705-709)
  - YMCA - US and International: Miscellaneous typescript and printed material, 1923-1951, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 710)
  - YMCA - US and International: Prayer fellowship letters, 1946-1959 (Box 45, Folder 711-712)
  - YMCA - US and International: Speaking engagements of LH, 1946-1949 (Box 45, Folder 713)
  - YMCA - US and International: World Service materials, 1938-1963, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 714-715)
  - YMCA - US and International: World Youth Fund materials, 1946-1948, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 716)
  - YMCA - US and International: Worship services, 1931-1958, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 718)
- Writings, 1918-1948; Series III
  The writings of this series are arranged alphabetically by title.
  - The American Student Christian Movement in Relation to the WSCF, 1933 (Box 46, Folder 719)
  - Among Mosques and Minarets (Box 46, Folder 720)
  - Chinese Followers of the Prophet, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 721)
  - Chinese Muslims and the War (Box 46, Folder 722)
  - Chinese Muslims Face a Great Decision, [1938?] (Box 46, Folder 723)
  - Chinese "Y's" Reconstruct Amid Turmoil, 1944 (Box 46, Folder 724)
  - Christian Vision and the College Curriculum, 1923 (Box 46, Folder 725)
  - Democritus and Atomism, 1948 (Box 46, Folder 726)
  - Fraternities and a Fraternal World, 1925 (Box 46, Folder 726)
  - Islam in China, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 727)
  - The Land Journey Between Szechuan and Shanghai, 1939 (Box 46, Folder 728)
  - A Month Under Sail, 1944 (Box 46, Folder 729)
  - The New Significance of Chinese Islam, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 730)
  - The Opportunity for World Service, 1918 (Box 46, Folder 730)
  - An Outline of Personal Belief, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 731)
  - Recent Developments in Christian Missions, c. 1924-1927 (Box 46, Folder 731)
  - Religion and Politics, 1922 (Box 46, Folder 732)
  - The Richness of the Christian Life, 1931 (Box 46, Folder 732)
  - Some Industrial Aspects of the Social Problem (Box 46, Folder 733)
  - Special Educational Preparation Needed by Westerners Serving as Missionaries in the Far East, 1948 (Box 46, Folder 734)
  - Western Attitudes Toward Chinese Political Character At the Close of the Manchu Dynasty, 1948 (Box 46, Folder 735)
  - Why It Is My Purpose, If God Permit, To Become a Foreign Missionary, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 736)
- Personal Items and Memorabilia, 1907-1976; Series IV
  A. Biographical material regarding Lyman Hoover: arranged chronologically (1907-1976)
  B. Diaries and appointment books
  1. Of Helen K. Hoover (1930-1964, n.d.)
  2. Of Lyman Hoover (1926-1974)
  C. Financial material
  1. Accounts (1925-1949, n.d.)
  2. Miscellaneous (1927-1967)
  D. Medical records
  1. Of Carol V. Hoover (1936-1948)
  2. Of Helen K. Hoover (1930-1948)
  3. Of Lyman Hoover (1930-1968, n.d.)
  E. Memorabilia
  1. Of Lyman Hoover's family (1933-1943)
  2. Of Helen K. Hoover (1920-1963)
  3. Of Lyman Hoover (1913-1962, n.d.)
  4. Legal documents (1930-1962)
  5. Passports, travel documents (1930-1966)
  F.Photographs
  1. Of family members (1919-1946, n.d.)
  2. General (1919-1970, n.d.)
  3. Related to Chinese Muslims (1931-1941, n.d.)
  - Biographical material, 1907-1930 (Box 47, Folder 737)
  - Biographical material, 1933-1976 (Box 47, Folder 738)
  - Biographical material, n.d. (Box 47, Folder 739)
  - Diaries and appointment books of HKH, 1930-1964, n.d. (Box 47, Folder 740-742)
  - Diaries and appointment books of LH, 1933-1961 (Box 48, Folder 743-748)
  - Diaries and appointment books of LH, 1962-1974 (Box 49, Folder 749-750)
  - Financial material: Accounts, 1925-1937 (Box 49, Folder 751-753)
  - Financial material: Accounts, 1944-1949, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 755-757)
  - Financial material: Miscellaneous, 1927, 1938-1949 (Box 50, Folder 758)
  - Financial material: Miscellaneous, 1949-1967 (Box 51, Folder 759)
  - Medical records of Carol V. Hoover, 1936-1948 (Box 51, Folder 760)
  - Medical records of Helen K. Hoover, 1930-1948 (Box 51, Folder 761)
  - Medical records of Lyman Hoover, 1930-1968,n.d. (Box 51, Folder 762-763)
  - Memorabilia of family of Lyman Hoover, 1933-1943 (Box 51, Folder 764)
  - Memorabilia of Helen K. Hoover, 1920-1963 (Box 51, Folder 765)
  - Memorabilia of Lyman Hoover, 1922-1962, n.d. (Box 51, Folder 766-767)
  - Memorabilia of Lyman Hoover - annotated books, 1913-1937, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 768)
  - Memorabilia: Legal documents, 1930-1962 (Box 53, Folder 769)
  - Memorabilia: Passports, travel documents, 1930-1966 (Box 53, Folder 770)
  - Memorabilia: Passports, travel documents -(Chinese language) (Box 53, Folder 771)
  - Photographs of family members, 1919-1946, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 772)
  - Photographs: General, 1919-1933 (Box 54, Folder 773-774)
  - Photographs: General, 1934-1970 (Box 55, Folder 775-776)
  - Photographs General - identified but undated (Box 55, Folder 777)
  - Photographs: General - unidentified, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 778-779)
  - Photographs: Related to Muslims in China, 1931-1941, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 780)
  - Chinese language pamphlets and journal issues (Box 57)